Just one place... just one place...
tatta hitotsu tatta hitotsu no...
Just one of me... just one of me...
tatta hitori tatta hitori no...
I'm right here.
watashi wa koko
With a chest made of rubble, I can't even breathe.
gareki no mune iki mo dekinai
The rain starts to fall, like a slumbering cry.
furidasu ame nemuru you ni cry
What flower should I decorate myself with
kono sekai o ikinuku no naraba
To stay alive in this world?
donna hana o kazareba ii no?
I want to believe, but still can't manage it...
shinjitai kuse ni shinjirarezu ni
My powerless and pointless self
muryoku de muimi na jibun ga
Still embraces my heart.
soredemo kokoro de idakun da
I can hear a voice calling to me, saying, "Come this way!"
"kocchi e oide" to koe ga kikoeru
A limitless and reckless tomorrow
mugen de mubou na ashita ga
Will still be waiting for me somewhere.
soredemo dokoka de matsu kara
Just one place... just one place...
tatta hitotsu tatta hitotsu no...
Just one of me... just one of me...
tatta hitori tatta hitori no...
I'm right here.
watashi wa koko
Take Chise to the land of dragons?
（エリアス）
チセをドラゴンの国へ？
（セルキー）はい
Yes.
Lindel-sama heard a rumor that the
Robin there has trouble using magic.
そこな愛し仔(ロビン)様が
どうやら魔法を使うのが不得手と
リンデル様が風のうわさを
お聞きになったのですよ
So he insists that you make a wand soon.
なので 早く杖(つえ)を作れと
おっしゃいましたのですよ
（チセ）杖？
A wand?
It's a tool for conveying your intentions to the fae.
（エリアス）
隣人たちに こちらの意図を
伝えるための道具だよ
He would like you to come see him, Robin.
（セルキー）
そういうことで
ロビン様に おいでになるようにと
I've been out all the time lately, though.
（エリアス）
最近 外に出てばかりだからなあ
Oh, don't worry about that.
あっ それは ご安心するのですよ
ロビン様 お一人だけでとの
仰せなのですよ
He wants the Robin to come alone.
Chise? By herself?
（エリアス）チセ１人で？
"I want to spend time with my
granddaughter, not with you," he says.
（セルキー）
“孫と遊ぶのに お前は邪魔！”
とのことですよ
That old bastard...
（エリアス）あのジジイ…
（チセ）
孫… じゃあ エリアスは息子なのか
Granddaughter?
So Elias is his son?
It seems he wants to talk about your
wand, though, so I suppose it's all right.
（エリアス）
本題は杖みたいだし 別にいいか
Take care.
気をつけて行っておいで
（エリアス）嫌かい？
Would you rather not?
いえ…
No, but by myself?
（チセ）
１人か…
You have me.
（ルツ）俺も いるだろう
（チセ）あっ… そうだね
Oh, right.
Are you done talking?
（ドラゴン）お話 終わった？
（チセ）うわっ
You sure haven't changed at all.
（ドラゴン）君 全然 変わらないね
（チセ）えっと…
Um...
Come on, have you forgotten me?
やだな 忘れたの？ お話もしたのに
We talked, remember?
You wouldn't fly with me, though.
滑空遊びは断られちゃったけどさ
Dragons grow up in various ways.
ドラゴンの成長は
まちまちなのですよ
I wanted to be big enough for you
to be able to ride me, so it works out.
君を乗せられるぐらい
大きくなれたらって思ってたから
ちょうどいいよ
そっか…
Yeah?
Thanks, Silky.
（チセ）ありがとう シルキー
Okay, I'll see you soon.
じゃあ いってきます
Take care.
（エリアス）いってらっしゃい
It's cold over there.
向こうは寒い
凍えないようにね
Don't freeze.
（チセ）はい
Okay.
Elias?
エリアス？
Yes?
（エリアス）何？
いえ…
It's nothing.
出発しますよ！
Let's go.
Hang on tight, so you don't fall off!
振り落とされないように
しっかり つかまるのですよ！
What's that?
（チセ）わっ 何？
It's a cloaking spell.
目くらましの術なのですよ
No one will find us now.
これで誰にも見つかりません
海を泳いで来るより
ずっと早いのですよ
It's a lot quicker than swimming through the sea.
（チセ）海？
The sea?
I'm a selkie.
自分はセルキー！
I'm a citizen of the great seas,
with both a human and seal form.
尊き海の民でありますれば
人とアザラシ
両の姿を持つものなのですよ
（チセ）あっ…
（セルキー）わあ！
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
風の間を抜けたら すぐ着くから
もう少し頑張って
We'll be there as soon as we get through the wind.
Hang on a little longer.
Okay.
（ルツ）エリアスなら大丈夫だろ
I'm sure Elias will be fine.
Yeah.
Lindel-sama!
（セルキー）リンデル様〜！
Lindel-sama, I did what you asked me to.
リンデル様
お使いできたのですよ 僕！
Yes, you did well. Very good.
（リンデル）
ああ よくできたの　偉いぞ
Hello, Lindel-san.
こんにちは リンデルさん
Chise.
チセ 久々だの
Long time no see.
You look quite well.
顔色も悪くないようだの
うむ… 肉もついたの
And you've put on some weight.
Good, good.
I'm glad to see you've found a good family.
良き家族も得たようで何よりだ
Lindel-san, where did you get those clothes?
（チセ）リンデルさん その服は…
Oh, I went shopping in town.
おお
町まで買い出しに行っておってな
男前じゃろ？
I'm very handsome, aren't I?
He kind of resembles Elias.
（チセ）
エリアスに ちょっと似てる
Come on, guys, say hi.
（リンデル）
ほれ おぬしら 挨拶しよれ
I'll be in your care.
（チセ）よろしくお願いします
I didn't get to explain last time.
（リンデル）
前は詳しくは話さなかったの
The land of dragons was established as
a nesting ground by the first administrator,
ドラゴンの国は
何百年か前に
最初の管理者が
for the few dragons that remained
scattered throughout the world.
世界に散る
わずかなドラゴンを移し
作った営巣地だ
So you weren't the one who made it, then?
リンデルさんが
作ったんじゃなかったんですね
わしは もともと
しがない遊牧の民よ
I used to be a simple nomad.
I didn't even have a name, until my master gave me one.
名すら持ち合わせておらなんだでな
師匠に もらったのよ
All right, we're here.
ほれ 着いたぞ
Nevin's tree.
（リンデル）ネヴィンの樹(き)だ
（チセ）わあ…
（セルキー）アハッ
I'll be preparing supper.
さて わしは夕餉(ゆうげ)の準備をする
（リンデル）チセ
（チセ）え… わっ！
Chise.
It's your wand. You've gotta cut it yourself.
己の杖は 己でな！
Are you okay?
（ルツ）大丈夫か〜？
Y-Yeah.
What is wrong with you?!
Who falls without even trying to break their fall?!
（ルツ）
受け身も取らず
そのまま落ちるヤツがあるか！
（チセ）い… 痛い ごめん
Ow.
Sorry.
You're so overprotective.
過保護ですねえ
It wouldn't kill her to get to know the rocks a little.
ちょっと岩と仲良くしたぐらいで
死にゃあしないのですよ
（ルツ）うるさい！
Shut up!
Should I go?
俺が行くか？
No, I'm going to be the one using it.
ううん 私が使うのだし
I'll see what I can do.
もうちょっと頑張るよ
（エリアス）
ああ ありがとう 銀の君
Thanks, Silver.
Boy, it's quiet.
何だか静かだね
Even though that girl is not very talkative.
あの子は
しゃべるほうじゃないのに…
The air feels terribly cold.
（エリアス）
ひどく空気が冷たく感じる
（アドルフ）
こんにちは
ミスター･エインズワース
Hello, Mr. Ainsworth.
My name is Adolf Stroud.
I'm with the College administration.
私はカレッジ管理局の
アドルフ･ストラウドと申します
College?
（エリアス）カレッジ？
I'll get straight to business.
（アドルフ）
単刀直入に申し上げます
I'd like to speak in depth about
the future of the human child.
人の子である彼女の将来について
深く お話しさせていただきたく
思います
Reindeer soup.
（リンデル）
トナカイのスープだ
食べたことはなかろう？
I imagine this is your first time having it.
（チセ）はい
Yes.
おいしい
It's good.
（リンデル）
む… すり傷だらけだの
見せてみい
You've got scrapes all over.
Let me see.
My hands are what's called healing hands.
わしの手は薬の手といってな
死なぬ傷なら たちどころに治る
As long as you aren't mortally
wounded, I can heal you on the spot.
There used to be more of us, before.
昔は
そういう者も多かったんだがの
ここ数百年は とんと生まれんの
But not many have been born
in the past few hundred years.
Have long have you been alive, Lindel-san?
（チセ）
リンデルさんは
いつから生きているんですか？
Are other mages long-lived, too?
ほかの魔法使いも みんな
長生きなんですか？
Oh, that's why you were making such a fuss earlier.
（セルキー）
ああ！ だから 今日
あんなに騒いでたのですね
That idiot!
（リンデル）
あのバカ骨め！
何も説明しとらんではないか
He hasn't explained anything!
これでは…
What does he...
（チセ）あっ えっと… すみません
Err, sorry, I should have asked Elias.
エリアスに聞かなかった私が
悪いんです
フウ…
Chise, the reason I brought you
here alone is because I'm worried.
チセ
この度 お前１人で呼んだのは
少し心配だったのよ
He seems to want to tame you, as one would a reindeer.
あれは どうも お前を
飼い慣らしたいように思うの
（リンデル）トナカイのように
（チセ）え？
And Chise, you seem to be content with that.
チセ
お前も また それを
よしとしておろう
The person who gave birth to me
told me that they shouldn't have.
（チセ）私は…
自分を産んだ人に
産まなきゃよかったと言われました
My mother didn't need me, so she ran away. She died.
お母さんは
いらない私から逃げて…
死んで
I think my brother and father ran away from me, too.
お父さんも 弟も
私から逃げたんだと思います
Elias is the only who's kept me nearby.
エリアスだけが
私を手元に置いてくれて…
That's why I don't ask him anything he doesn't say.
だから 私は あのヒトが
言わないことは聞かないし
I want to be complacent.
都合のいい人間でいたいんです
Though it doesn't appear that way at all.
（リンデル）
とても そんなふうに見えんがの
I'll tell you an interesting bedtime story.
（リンデル）
寝物語に
１つ面白い話をしてやろう
An interesting story?
（チセ）面白い話？
I suppose I'll answer your question, too.
（リンデル）そうよの…
先ほどの問いの答えもやろう
But, half of it is as punishment for that
bastard, for saddening my granddaughter.
が… 半分は娘っ子を悲しませる
あれへの罰だの
まだ世界は はるか遠く暗く
Long ago, when the world was still dark,
before the power of steam, and before
even the power of the old, earthen oil...
蒸気の力も
太古の地層より湧く油もない時代だ
We mages were all aware
that we were not normal people.
古(いにしえ)より 我々魔法使いは
自らは只人(ただびと)ではないと
おのずから悟るものだった
For we saw magical creatures, and worked
miracles that the ordinary person could not.
それは 妖(あやか)しの者どもを
見るためであったり
只人には行えぬ奇跡を
なせるからでもあり
And at times, we lived very long lives.
ときに 非常に永く
生きるためであったりした
We don't know why we're so long-lived,
or possess abilities humans do not.
なぜ我々が人間より
長命で頑健であるかは分からん
It may simply be that fate wanted us to be born so.
ただ そう生まれつく
さだめだっただけかもしれぬ
But those who were not
satisfied continued to seek an answer.
だが 納得できぬ者は
理由を探し続けた
"Why are we so?"
なぜ自分がそうなのか
"Is there a duty that we must fulfill?"
何か果たすべき使命が
あるのでは… とな
Many of our kind perished in their search.
それを探し 同胞が
幾人も伏していった
I wandered alone, sick of that way of life.
（リンデル）
わしが まだ その道理を嫌って
１人 遊牧の旅をしていたころだ
One night, there were wolves, and I
had no choice but to stand watch all night.
ある夜 オオカミが出て
夜通し 番をするはめになった
However, the wolves never came.
だが オオカミは来なかった
Instead, it came.
代わりに あれが来た
It came as certain as night on two legs.
それは 夜が二つ足で歩むがごとく
やって来た
おぬしは…
You...
What's the matter?
（リンデル）おい どうした？
I'm hungry.
（エリアス）おなか すいた…
Hey!
お… おい！
気が付いたかの
You're awake, huh?
You were asleep all night.
夜通し 寝とったぞ
You're so huge, it was a pain to carry you.
図体(ずうたい)がデカくて 運ぶに骨が折れた
Aren't you going to eat?
食わんのか？
Where did you come from?
おぬし どこから来た？
（エリアス）分からない
（リンデル）ん？
I don't know.
When I came to, I was in the forest, and I was walking.
（エリアス）
気が付いたら森にいて
いつの間にか歩いてた
Avoiding people, I walked,
walked, and walked, until I was here.
人をよけて歩いて 歩いて…
歩いたら ここにいた
I'm tired.
もう 疲れた
どうした？
What's wrong?
Nothing.
（エリアス）何でもない
You look to be an apparition of some kind.
（リンデル）
見たところ お前は妖しの者だが
生き物と同じように
肉を まとっているようだ
But you wear flesh, like a living creature.
What are you?
お前は何者だ？
（エリアス）分からない
I don't know.
（リンデル）ふむ…
とりあえず
わしの師匠のもとへ行こう
Well, let's go see my master.
She's a strange one.
あれは よく分からないお人でな
住んでいるのが地の裏かも
すぐそばなのかもしれぬし
She may be at the other side of
the world. She may be right there.
She may be alive a hundred years
from now or a hundred years ago.
生きておるのは
100年後か 100年前かもしれぬ
Being a meddler, she may provide guidance.
おせっかいゆえ 身の振り方を
教えてもらえるやもしれん
I'd imagine it would be less painful
than aimlessly wandering through the wilds.
行く当てもなく
ただ荒野を さまようのは
つらかろうしな
Who are you?
（エリアス）君… は？
わしはリンデル
I'm Lindel.
只人は わしらのような者たちを
魔法使いと呼ぶのう
The ordinary people call us "mages."
What is that?
（エリアス）それは…
An ancient technique for finding the missing.
（リンデル）
古の失(う)せもの探しの法じゃ
トウヒを束ね
赤い毛糸を巻いて放つ
Gather some spruce, tie it in red string, and set it loose.
地を覆うトウヒは森の神の食卓
The spruce covering the ground
is the dining table of the forest god.
お力を借り 道を尋ねる
We ask for their help and for directions.
My guide, take us past the fog, to the one we seek.
導くものよ
霧の向こうの我が縁者のもとへ
連れてゆきたもう
The fog is thickening.
（リンデル）
霧が濃くなる　離れるなよ
Stay with me.
（エリアス）水…
Water.
The sea.
（リンデル）
海だ　なめてみい 面白いぞ
Have a taste.
It's fun.
ブヘッ
（エリアス）ゲホッ ゲホッ…
（リンデル）ハハハハ
That's my master's home.
あれが師の家だ
Master.
師よ ラハブよ　いるかの
Rahab.
Are you home?
（ラハブ）リンデルか
Is that Lindel?
I don't see your face here often.
珍しいね
お前が ここに顔を見せるなんて
集会場の樹の名が泣く
A pity, since your name's derived
from that of the tree of gatherings.
That name was your choice, Master.
師が選んだ名じゃろうが
You need to make an effort
to interact with people more—
お前は もっと人と関わる努力を…
おや？
Oh?
I found him yesterday.
（リンデル）昨日 拾ったんじゃ
I wanted you to take a look at him.
こやつのことを見てもらいたくての
（ラハブ）ふうむ…
Come in.
入っておいで… と言いたいけど
君 大きいな
Though then again, you're pretty big.
小さくなれるかい？
Can you become smaller?
Smaller?
（エリアス）小さく？
That's right.
（ラハブ）そう 人間ぐらい
About human size.
Human...
（エリアス）にんげん…
ほう…
（エリアス）これ？
Like this?
Yes.
うん よくできたね
Well done.
おいで
Come.
You don't know?
分からない？
（ラハブ）
そうだな…
限りなく精霊や妖精寄りなんだけど
Well...
He's as close to a spirit or fairy as you
can get, but there's a hint of human in him.
でも わずかに人間が入ってる
人間が愚かな邪法のしっぺ返しで
化けた…
It would make sense if he
were simply a human who'd gotten
himself transformed trying to use black magic.
というのなら話は簡単なんだけど
逆に これは…
But this seems more like...
Do you remember anything about
what happened before you started walking?
君が歩きだす前に何があったか
覚えていることがあるかい？
Anything I remember?
（エリアス）覚えてる… こと…
赤…
Red.
赤？
Red?
You don't have to force yourself to remember.
（ラハブ）
無理に思い出さずともいいさ
Lindel, you'll take care of him.
（ラハブ）リンデル
（リンデル）ん？
お前
この子の面倒を見てあげなさい
Huh?
えっ？ なぜ わしが！
Why me?
（ラハブ）
一度 慈悲をかけたなら
独り立ちまで面倒を見るべきだ
You've already taken pity on him once.
You ought to take care of him until he's independent.
I have to follow the reindeer.
わしはトナカイを追わねばならん
（ラハブ）
お前も そろそろ
弟子を取っていいころだ
It's about time you took an apprentice.
We ought not to live by ourselves.
我々は
独りで生きるべきではないんだ
Remember what I taught you?
教えただろう
I won't tell you to love your enemy.
“汝(なんじ)の敵を愛せ”とは言わない
But the neighbors love us.
だが
我々は隣人たちから愛されている
We lend a staff to those who have lost their way.
行き先に迷う者には
杖を貸すのが我々だ
（リンデル）
望んで愛されたわけではなかろう
It's not as if we asked to be loved.
わしも おぬしも 皆…
Not me nor you.
呪われているような
ものだ
We might as well be cursed.
Curses and blessings are the same in essence, Lindel.
呪いも祝福も
本質は 一緒だよ リンデル
どう受け止めるかだ
What matters is how you take it.
It's fine.
（エリアス）いいよ 僕は行く
I'm going.
If you'd rather not have me here, I'll continue walking.
僕が いないほうがいいのなら
僕は また歩くよ
To where?
（リンデル）どこへ？
I don't know, but you're busy, aren't you?
（エリアス）分からないけど
君は忙しいんでしょ
I don't take apprentices.
わ… わしは弟子なんぞ取れん
So from now on, you're my acquaintance.
だから おぬしは…
今から わしの知人だ
I would surely have to provide a
weary acquaintance a place to sleep.
旅に疲れきった知人がいるなら
寝床ぐらい貸さなければの
I'm not in need.
（エリアス）僕は困ってないよ
You're one to talk. You collapsed!
（リンデル）
倒れたくせに どの口が言う
Oh my, how kind of you.
あらまあ 優しいねえ
（リンデル）うるさい
Shut up!
Now that that's settled, we're friends.
（ラハブ）
そうと決まれば
お前は もう身内だね
What's your name?
名前は…
I'm guessing you don't have one.
なさそうだね　どうしよっか？
What should we call you?
（リンデル）
また師の名付け好きが
始まりおった…
Here we go again, with Master's name-giving obsession.
The gods and the fairies are all with you.
神々も精霊たちも
君の すぐそばにいる
Even if no one takes notice of you,
誰も君を顧みることがなくとも
even if you're sad, suffering, and crushed
by loneliness, they will always watch over you.
苦しく 悲しく
寂しさに あえいでも
彼らは君を いつも見ていてくれる
だから
安心して自分自身を救いなさい
So take comfort, and save yourself.
エリアス
Elias.
Hello? Ainsworth?
（レンフレッド）
おい エインズワース
（アドルフ）
ああ 先輩！ 勝手に…
Senpai! Stop!
（エリアス）レンフレッド
Renfred.
You're going to ruin her if you continue to
do nothing more than let her live with you.
（レンフレッド）
このまま
お前と暮らすだけにさせていたら
彼女はダメになるぞ
To keep the seeds I tie to this branch
eda ni musubu mi ga jukusu mae ni
From falling before they ripen
ochite shimawanu you
I bloom again in profusion, painfully
kurushii hodo ni mata sakimidareru
To connect myself to tomorrow.
asa e tsunagu you
Even as they're born again
nando kurikaeshi
And again,
kurikaeshi umaretemo
I'll always show them
itsumo atarashii
A brand new sky.
sora o misete ageyou
I'll pen a story that no one,
daremo mada daremo
No one has ever written.
kaitenai monogatari
On a map so white, pure white,
shiroi masshiroi
I'll draw it out, singing it aloud.
chizu ni kaite utaou
The story of the mage's past.
（チセ）
語られた魔法使いの過去
The girl is shaken by the truth that had been hidden.
隠されてきた真実に
少女の心は震える
つかの間の離別が
２人に もたらすのは…
What does the brief parting bring to the two?
I'll tell you what I haven't been able to tell you, too.
（チセ）
私も あなたに言えてなかったこと
話します